Angela Robinette

Front End Developer

Email: angela@dev-angela.com/ Website: https://dev-angela.com/

Profile: * HTML * CSS * JavaScript * Accessibility * Security

Software developer with over 10 years' experience in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Passionate about creating aesthetically pleasing and functional websites which enhance a user's experience while providing special attention to accessibility and security. Previous experience in software development, graphics, UX/UI design, and mentorship roles.

Skills:

HTML5	CSS3	JavaScript	Bootstrap	Angular
PaintShop Pro	Figma	Git	GitHub & GitLab	Google
Visual Studio Code	FileZilla			

Education:

Purdue University Global **Associate of Applied Science in Information Technology – Programming and Software Development** Summa Cum Laude *March*, 2022

Coursera Google Certification - Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design June, 2022

Experience:

Full-stack Developer for JM Insurance Group March 2022- Present

Refreshed the website and converted it from .Net to vanilla HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Updated request quote form with accessibility and security in mind. Future plan to add a CRUD blog to allow for employees to add, update, and delete entries.

Front-end developer for KidzBux January 2021 – Present

From design to implementation, working on the front-end for this app using Figma and Angular.

SofDev Mentor for PGIP-Tech *January 2022 – Present*

Guided 14+ interns in various coding experiences, including object-oriented programming issues, React, UI/UX design, accessibility awareness and testing, front-end security awareness and testing, and the importance of "Googling" questions and solutions to coding errors.

Owner/Designer/Developer for Dev-angela.com January 2022 - Present

Designed personal portfolio website, coded in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and jQuery, launched using FileZilla.

SofDev Manager for PGIP-Tech Internship October 14, 2021 – December 21, 2021

Kept interns on track assigned tasks, worked with Docker, PHP, Git/GitLab and MySQLi on group project, and helped interns pick a path and the stack they needed.

Student at Purdue University Global July 2020 – March 2022

Learned to write and edit SQL relational databases using MySQL Server, the concepts of object-oriented programming (C#) using VS 2019, how to code, test, and debug HTML, CSS, and JS by hand using Notepad, how to recode non-responsive websites with Flexbox, and how to create a portfolio website.